import 'package:my_protfolio1/model/question.dart';
import 'package:my_protfolio1/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. What is the official language of Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Bengali',
      'b) Hindi',
      'c) Urdu',
      'd) English',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. Which river is the longest in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Jamuna (Brahmaputra)',
      'b) Padma (Ganges)',
      'c) Meghna',
      'd) Surma',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. What is the currency of Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Rupee',
      'b) Taka',
      'c) Ringgit',
      'd) Baht',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. Which famous mangrove forest is located in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Amazon Rainforest',
      'b) Sundarbans',
      'c) Borneo Rainforest',
      'd) Congo Rainforest',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Who is known as the "Father of the Nation" in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Sheikh Mujibur Rahman',
      'b) Ziaur Rahman',
      'c) Sheikh Hasina',
      'd) Khaleda Zia',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. Which UNESCO World Heritage Site is located in Bagerhat, Bangladesh, known for its historical mosques and structures?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Lalbagh Fort',
      'b) Ahsan Manzil',
      'c) Historic Mosque City of Bagerhat',
      'd) Mahasthangarh',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. What is the national flower of Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Rose',
      'b) Water Lily (Shapla)',
      'c) Jasmine',
      'd) Orchid',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. In which year did Bangladesh gain independence from Pakistan?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) 1969',
      'b) 1971',
      'c) 1980',
      'd) 1990',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. What is the name of the largest delta in the world, located in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Amazon Delta',
      'b) Mekong Delta',
      'c) Nile Delta',
      'd) Sundarbans Delta',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10. What is the highest mountain in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Mount Everest',
      'b) Saka Haphong',
      'c) Keokradong',
      'd) Tazing Dong',
    ],
  ),
];
